U.S. Emergency Board No. 145 Records 5060
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Emergency Board No. 145 Records
1961
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Emergency Board
5060
3 cubic feet
3 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Transcript of proceedings and exhibits of the Emergency Board No. 144,1961. Akron and Barberton Belt Railroad and other carriers represented by Eastern, Western, and Southeastern Carriers' Conference Committees vs. Eleven Cooperating Railway Labor Organizations, 1949-1962.
3115423
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Jeffrey Stark, January 29, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Biographical / Historical
On September 1, 1961 the Organizations served the Carriers with a "Section 6 Notice," giving the customary 30 day notice, of a desire to revise and supplement all existing agreements, effective November 1, 1961 in two respects; (l) All pay rates to be raised 25 cents per hour on that date, and (2) Six month's notice to be given to employees to be affected by a reduction in force or abolition of positions, except in certain emergency situations.
The Carriers made the following counter proposals; (l) Reduce by SO per cent the rates of pay of certain groups of middle and lower range employees, (2) Establish entry rates for seven groups at 80 per cent of existing rates, to be increased by 4 per cent per annum until established rates are reached, (3) Establish flat $1.25 hourly rate for diner car waiters and others who serve food and drinks, and (4) Eliminate all rules or provisions which require more than 24 hour advance notice prior to abolition of positions or reduction of force.
On September 21, 1961 the Organizations invited the Carriers to meet on the issues. On October 5, the Carrier replied that they would consider the matter later. On October 10, 1961 the Organizations invoked mediation.
The parties met in Washington, D. C. on January 10, 1962 to negotiate, where virtually nothing was accomplished. The Organizations declined the National Mediation Board's offer of arbitration whereupon certification of the dispute to the President and the appointment of the Emergency Board followed.
The Board consisting of Saul Wallen, Chairman, and Laurence E. Seibel and Edward A. Lynch met with the parties in Chicago on March 6, 1962. Hearings were held there and in Washington for a total of 15 days. The Board also attempted to mediate the differences between the parties but failed. The Board issued its report on May 3, 1962.
Scope and Contents
On September 1, 1961 the Organizations served the Carriers with a "Section 6 Notice," giving the customary 30 day notice, of a desire to revise and supplement all existing agreements, effective November 1, 1961 in two respects; (l) All pay rates to be raised 25 cents per hour on that date, and (2) Six month's notice to be given to employees to be affected by a reduction in force or abolition of positions, except in certain emergency situations. The Carriers made the following counter proposals; (l) Reduce by SO per cent the rates of pay of certain groups of middle and lower range employees, (2) Establish entry rates for seven groups at 80 per cent of existing rates, to be increased by 4 per cent per annum until established rates are reached, (3) Establish flat $1.25 hourly rate for diner car waiters and others who serve food and drinks, and (4) Eliminate all rules or provisions which require more than 24 hour advance notice prior to abolition of positions or reduction of force. On September 21, 1961 the Organizations invited the Carriers to meet on the issues. On October 5, the Carrier replied that they would consider the matter later. On October 10, 1961 the Organizations invoked mediation. The parties met in Washington, D. C. on January 10, 1962 to negotiate, where virtually nothing was accomplished. The Organizations declined the National Mediation Board's offer of arbitration whereupon certification of the dispute to the President and the appointment of the Emergency Board followed. The Board consisting of Saul Wallen, Chairman, and Laurence E. Seibel and Edward A. Lynch met with the parties in Chicago on March 6, 1962. Hearings were held there and in Washington for a total of 15 days. The Board also attempted to mediate the differences between the parties but failed. The Board issued its report on May 3, 1962.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5006: U.S. Emergency Board No. 174 Records 5007: U.S. Emergency Board No. 175 Transcripts and Exhibits 5012: Saul Wallen Papers 5027: U.S. Emergency Board No. 178 Transcripts 5030: U.S. Emergency Board No. 179 Exhibits and Related Material 5036: U.S. Emergency Boards under the Railway Labor Act Reports 5037: U.S. Emergency Board No. 81 Records 5038: U.S. Emergency Board No. 94 Records 5039: U.S. Emergency Board No. 98 Records 5040: U.S. Emergency Board No. 106 Records 5042: U.S. Emergency Board No. 111 Records 5043: U.S. Emergency Board No. 114 Records 5044: U.S. Emergency Board No. 116 Reports and Exhibits 5045: U.S. Emergency Board No. 118 Records 5046: U.S. Emergency Board No. 119 Records 5047: U.S. Emergency Board No. 120 Records 5048: U.S. Emergency Board No. 121 Records 5050: U.S. Emergency Board No. 124 Records 5051: U.S. Emergency Board No. 125 Records 5052: U.S. Emergency Board No. 129 Records 5053: U.S. Emergency Board No. 130 Records 5054: U.S. Emergency Board No. 133 Exhibits 5055: U.S. Emergency Board No. 134 Records 5056: U.S. Emergency Board No. 135 Records 5057: U.S. Emergency Board No. 137 Transcript of Proceedings and Exhibits 5058: U.S. Emergency Board No. 138 Records 5059: U.S. Emergency Board No. 142 Records 5061: U.S. Emergency Board No. 146 Records 5062: U.S. Emergency Board No. 154 Records 5064: U.S. Emergency Board No. 169 Transcript of Proceedings and Exhibits 5075: U.S. Emergency Board under the Taft Hartley Act Records 5579: National Mediation Board Emergency Board 180, Train Crew Consists 5934: Arthur Stark Papers on the President's Emergency Board #219
Arbitration, Industrial--United States--Sources.; Railroads--Employees--Labor unions--United States--Sources.; United States. Emergency Board No. 145.
3115423
- Transcripts and Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Transcripts. 15 volumes. 2,649 pages. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 1. Pre-hearing memorandum. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 2. Order, awards, agreements, and reports relating to the rates of pay of railroads non-operating employees. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 3. Subject of Carriers' Exhibit 2 continued. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 4. Job description and illustrative examples of payroll position and duties. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 5. Miscellaneous materials relating to job content. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 6. Testimony - Job content and working conditions of railroad non-operating employees. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 7. Miscellaneous statistical data - Chicago and North Western Railroad Company. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 8. Eastern Railroads Financial Condition and Ability to Pay. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 9. Supplementary Materials Inter-Industry-Wage Earnings Comparisons. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 10. Inter-Industry-Wage and Earning Comparisons. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 11. National Office Management Association Survey of Rates of Pay of Clerical Employees in all Industries in 56 Cities. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 12. Special Study - 26 Carriers, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Scope and Contents
    September, 1961.
  - Carrier's Exhibit 13. Wage Comparison - Selected Railroad Classes - All Industry Employees included in Bureau of Labor Statistics Survey, 82 Labor Markets., 1960- 1961 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 14. Carrier's Step Rate Proposal. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 15. Wage Rates and Other Information (State Highway Maintenance Employees). (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 16. Regional Comparisons Relating to 20 Per Cent Reduction and Step Rate Classifications (Chesapeake and Ohio Railway - Seaboard Air Line Railroad). (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 17. Statement: Regional Comparison Relating to 20 Per Cent Reduction and Step Rate Classifications (Chesapeake and Ohio Railway-Seaboard Air Line Railroad). (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 18. Wage Data and Related Material Pertaining to Wage Adjustments Proposed by the Carriers. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Labor Markets Served by Illinois Central Railroad Company and Chicago, Burlington, and Quincy Railroad Company.
  - Carrier's Exhibit 19. Testimony of E.H. Hallmann relating to Wage Adjustments Proposed by carriers (Subject matter contained in Exhibit 18). (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 20. Comparative Data Relating to Carriers' Wage Adjustment Proposals 12 Eastern Markets. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 21. Carriers' Proposals (Food and Beverage Service Personnel, Kitchen Helpers). (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 22. Statement on Carriers' Proposals Assignment and Job Task Comparisons (Food and Beverage Service Personnel). (Subject matter in Exhibit 21). (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 23. Carriers' Proposals (Food and Beverage Service Personnel) (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Titles, Rates and Schedule Hours - Wage Level and Progress Comparisons - Financial Condition of Rail Dining Car Service.
  - Carrier's Exhibit 24. Statement on Carriers' Proposals (Food and Beverage Service Personnel) (subject matter in Exhibit 23). (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 25. Hospital, Medical, and Surgical Plan, Paid Holidays and Other Employee Benefits. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Carrier's Exhibit 26. Retirement, Unemployment and Sickness Benefits in the Railroad Industry. (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Carrier's Exhibits and Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Employee's Exhibit 1. Proposals of Employees and Carrier Counter Proposals. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Employee's Exhibit 2. Classification and Number of Non-Operating Employees. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Employee's Exhibit 3. Job Descriptions of Typical Occupations in the Shop Craft and Firemen and Oiler Classifications in the Railroad Industry. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Employee's Exhibit 4. No information available. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Employee's Exhibit 5. Methods and Standards for Inter-Industry Wage comparison. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Employee's Exhibit 6. Wage Supplement Comparisons. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Employee's Exhibit 7. Wage Trends - Non-Operating Railway Employees and other Comparable American Workers., 1949-1958 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    September 1949-December 1958.
  - Employee's Exhibit 8. Wage Developments., 1959 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Employee's Exhibit 9. Wage Developments., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Employee's Exhibit 10. Wage Developments., 1961 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Employee's Exhibit 11. Wage Progress - Non-Operating Railway Employees and other Comparable American Workers., 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Employee's Exhibit 12. Instability of Employment of Non-Operating Railway Classes. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Employee's Exhibit 13. Employment Stabilization Developments in the Railroad Industry. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Employee's Exhibit 14. Employment Stabilization in other American Industries. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Employee's Exhibit 15. Mail Handling - Kansas City Terminal. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Employee's Exhibit 16. Productivity of Railway Employees. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Employee's Exhibit 17. Wages, Unit Costs, and Price Levels. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Employee's Exhibit 18. Real Wages. Health, Education, and Welfare of American Workers. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Employee's Exhibit 19. Railroad Participation in Intercity Freight Traffic. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Employee's Exhibit 20. Financial Position of American Railways. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Employee's Exhibit 21. Railroad Physical Properties and Equipment. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Employee's Exhibit 22. Railroad Outlook to Investors (Including Railroad Officials). (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Employee's Exhibit 23. Hourly Wage Rates for Selected Jobs Negotiated by the International Association of Machinists, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Reported as of October 31, 1961.
  - Employee's Exhibit 24. Hourly Wage Rates for Selected Jobs Negotiated by the International Association of Machinists., 1961 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Reported after October 31, 1961.
  - Miscellaneous: Report to the President. 1 volume, 28 pages plus appendix. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous: Wages and Related Benefits - 82 Labor Markets., 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous: Editorial Reaction to Report of the Emergency Board. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous: Mediation Agreement between Southern Pacific Company (Pacific Lines) and the Order of Railroad Telegraphers. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous: "The Move Toward Railroad Mergers - A Great National Problem" by Railway Labor Executives' Association. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous: Letter from National Mediation Board to Emergency Board. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous: Letter from Sullivan Reporting Company to Saul Wallen. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous: Stipulation as to the Report of the Board. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous: Information for Emergency Boards and Boards of Arbitration (from National Mediation Board) (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous: Memorandum from National Mediation Board. (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Notes and Letters of Saul Wallen (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Carrier's Exhibits and Employee's Exhibits (Box 3)